Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Finance]

Notice Period: More than 3 Months

Sri Ramya Ravinuthala (1) Featured

Senior Consultant seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement

Gathering, System

Analysis, Agile, SDLC, Java, J2EE, Spring, Struts, Servlet, JSP, HTML, CSS, Oracle, Tomcat, Weblogic, Sonard

Current Designation: Senior Consultant -IT

Current Company: Capgemini

Current Location: Chennai

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Consultant, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Program

Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System

Analysis, Agile, SDLC, Java, J2EE, Spring, Struts, Servlet, JSP, HTML, CSS, Oracle, Tomcat, Weblogic, Sonar Qube

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Having 6 years of experience in the development of Web and Enterprise applications using Java/J2EE technologies.

Strong knowledge in Banking and Financial services domain.

Rich experience in the development of J2EE applications using technologies and frameworks like Spring, Web Services etc.

Strong exposure to Agile Methodology.

Experience in SDLC.

Strong debugging skills and ability to provide efficient designs.

Capability in gathering and analysing data.

Skill in providing application support whenever required.

Pleasing personality with zest for life and sound understanding of technology.

I am adaptable to any kind of situation and also an enthusiastic learner of new techniques and technologies.

I have played an active role as a team member as well as a leader by guiding the team associates with my leadership qualities.

Work Experience

Cappemini as Senior Consultant -IT

Dec 2018 to Till Date

Exhibited leadership qualities as team lead.

Innovated an application which minimized the testing effort.

Played a major role in the development of an enhancement project.

Strong exposure to agile methodology. Participated in all agile discussion like Scrum, grooming, planning and retrospective calls.

Strong experience in guiding team members efficiently.

Participated in all business requirements discussion.

E commerce application for Digital Retail Cards: - Jan 17th 2019 - Till Date

Client: Synchrony Financial, US Role: Senior Consultant/ Developer Technologies: Struts, JAVA, J2EE, SQL.

Project Description:

Digital RC platform ensures that online transactions are made error free. Two separate versions of application for Desktop

and Mobile services are developed. This is front end application where user can login and find his transactions on timely basis. This project ensures that defect leakage is nil and rich UI experience. More than 100+ clients are handled. This project also supports features like, Payments, view statements online, Balance transfer, Rewards redemption etc.

Responsibilities:

Hands on experience in agile methodology. Experience in managing the Team efficiently.

Handled major requirements like Balance Transfer, Rewards etc.

Nil production defects/issues reported.

TATA Consultancy Services Limited as Systems Engineer/Developer

Jun 2014 to Dec 2018

Involved in the application development activity for banking domain as a java developer.

Having a major role in the development of an enhancement project which is interrelated to many other systems.

Owned a project which changed the look and feel of the existing application.

Strong exposure to all the phases of SDLC.

IOWA: - International Operations Workflow Application

Sep 9th 2014 - Dec 21st 2018

Client: Citi Bank, London Role: IT Analyst/Developer

Technologies: Spring, JAVA, SQL, JMS, TIBCO EMS

Project Description:

IOWA is a back end application used for trade marketing, with production deployments twice every month. This project requires application support at the time of application shutdown and deploying the code to production environment. This project ensures timely deployments to tester environment with nil leakage. This project accepts inputs from upstream systems and enhances the trade processing.

Responsibilities:

Hands on experience in Coding and unit testing.

Received client appreciation for handling emergency requirements and delivering it on time without major issues.

Delivered requirements on time.

Experience in using Sonar qube.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Koneru Lakshmaiah College of Engineering (KLCE), Arni in

PG: MBA/PGDM (Finance) in 0

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Java , J2EE, Spring, Struts			
Servlet, JSP, HTML, JS, CSS			
restful webservices			
Oracle Sql, Tomcat, Weblogic			
SonarQube			
Eclipse IDE, SQL Developer, Putty,Tectia			
SVN, GIT			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
----------	-------------	------	-------	-------	--

1/22/2021	https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=281ef22432521a2b5843acd236ce17a75d0b5d58191b0e450544490a5				
English					
Hindi					
Telugu					

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization